<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixed or Random Effect, or Both?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/23/fixed-effect-random-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/23/fixed-effect-random-effect/</guid>
      <description>Panel data When we have a panel data (repeated observations over time, or observations clustered at higher level), we usually think of two choices: random effect or fixed effect? Economists usually prefers fixed effect models, since it wipes out all within unit heterogeneity. Economists do not like random effect models since it has a big assumption: the random effects need to be uncorrelated to other covariates in the model. To see this, suppose we have</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction term in a non-linear model</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/interaction-term-in-a-non-linear-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/interaction-term-in-a-non-linear-model/</guid>
      <description>Interaction term in a non-linear model In a non-linear model (for example, logit or poisson model), the interpretation of the coefficient on the interaction term is tricky. Ai and Norton (2003) points out that the interaction term coefficient is not the same as people can interpret as in a linear model; that is, how much effect of \(x1\) changes with the value of \(x2\). They interpret this as a cross</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting interaction in a regression model</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/interpreting-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/interpreting-interaction/</guid>
      <description>Interaction with two binary variables In a regression model with interaction term, people tend to pay attention to only the coefficient of the interaction term.
Let’s start with the simpliest situation: \(x_1\) and \(x_2\) are binary and coded 0/1.
\[ E(y) = \beta_1 x_1 + \beta_2 x_2 + \beta_{12} x_1x_2 \]
In this case, we have a saturated model; that is, we have three coefficients representing additive effects from the baseline situation (both \(x_1\) and \(x_2\) being 0).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
