<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stata on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/categories/stata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stata on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/stata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed or Random Effect, or Both?</title>
      <link>/2019/05/23/fixed-effect-random-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/23/fixed-effect-random-effect/</guid>
      <description>Panel data When we have a panel data (repeated observations over time, or observations clustered at higher level), we usually think of two choices: random effect or fixed effect? Economists usually prefers fixed effect models, since it wipes out all within unit heterogeneity. Economists do not like random effect models since it has a big assumption: the random effects need to be uncorrelated to other covariates in the model. To see this, suppose we have</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Marginal effects with margins command</title>
      <link>/2019/04/22/marginal-effects-in-margins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/22/marginal-effects-in-margins/</guid>
      <description>Comparing Marginal effects Stata’s margins command has been a powerful tool for many economists. It can calculate predicted means as well as predicted marginal effects. Sometimes we’d like to compare those marginal effects. People use margins and marginsplot to generate marginal effects; then draw conclusions on whether there is a difference between marginal effects, based on whether the confidence intervals overlap or not. However, that can actually be wrong. In this post, I’d like to introduce a way to compare effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marginal effects in models with fixed effects</title>
      <link>/2019/01/25/marginal-effects-in-models-with-fixed-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/25/marginal-effects-in-models-with-fixed-effects/</guid>
      <description>Marginal effects in a linear model Stata’s margins command has been a powerful tool for many economists. It can calculate predicted means as well as predicted marginal effects. However, we do need to be careful when we use it when fixed effects are included. In a linear model, everything works out fine. However, in a non-linear model, you may not want to use margins, since it’s not calculating what you have in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment effects and matching</title>
      <link>/2019/01/10/treatment-effects-with-matching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/10/treatment-effects-with-matching/</guid>
      <description>Treatment effects in observational studies Despite the popularity of randomized experiements in economics nowadays, most situations we have observational data in economic studies. One reason is experiemnts are expensive; the other reason is that sometimes it is simply not feasible to have experiments. If we have observational data, and we’d like to draw causal conclusions, then we have a few different situations. The worse situation is that we have an endogenous treatement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction term in a non-linear model</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/interaction-term-in-a-non-linear-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/interaction-term-in-a-non-linear-model/</guid>
      <description>Interaction term in a non-linear model In a non-linear model (for example, logit or poisson model), the interpretation of the coefficient on the interaction term is tricky. Ai and Norton (2003) points out that the interaction term coefficient is not the same as people can interpret as in a linear model; that is, how much effect of \(x1\) changes with the value of \(x2\). They interpret this as a cross</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting interaction in a regression model</title>
      <link>/2017/12/07/interpreting-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/07/interpreting-interaction/</guid>
      <description>Interaction with two binary variables In a regression model with interaction term, people tend to pay attention to only the coefficient of the interaction term.
Let’s start with the simpliest situation: \(x_1\) and \(x_2\) are binary and coded 0/1.
\[ E(y) = \beta_1 x_1 + \beta_2 x_2 + \beta_{12} x_1x_2 \]
In this case, we have a saturated model; that is, we have three coefficients representing additive effects from the baseline situation (both \(x_1\) and \(x_2\) being 0).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>